<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Octavian Tocan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Octavian Tocan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Octavian Tocan&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Octavian Tocan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Helping AI help me make games</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home-page-list/helping-ai-help-me-make-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home-page-list/helping-ai-help-me-make-games/</guid>
      <description>Helping AI help me make games</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realistic Assault Rifle Template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/realistic-assault-rifle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/realistic-assault-rifle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After years of low-poly assets, we decided to go realistic. This template features high-fidelity graphics,
modular weapon attachments, and professional-grade animations. Includes advanced movement mechanics like sliding,
vaulting, and tactical sprint. The biggest challenge was balancing visual fidelity with performance—turns out
realistic graphics require realistic optimization efforts. &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Download the free demo&lt;/a&gt; to see if it&amp;rsquo;s right for your project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Poly Shooter Pack v6.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/low-poly-shooter-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/low-poly-shooter-pack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What started as a simple FPS template turned into our flagship product. Thousands of developers use it to build
their shooter games without spending months on basic mechanics. Features 18 weapons, multiplayer support, AI enemies,
and 240+ weapon materials. From prototypes to published games, it&amp;rsquo;s been quite the journey watching developers
build amazing things with it. &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Try the free demo&lt;/a&gt; or check out the &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;full template on the marketplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unreal Engine Performance Profiler</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/unreal-performance-profiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/unreal-performance-profiler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Started as a simple FPS counter overlay for debugging frame drops in projects. Ended up as a comprehensive
performance monitoring suite after discovering that measuring performance&amp;hellip; impacts performance. Go figure.
Went through multiple iterations before finally cracking non-intrusive monitoring with async profiling.
Currently optimizing the UI rendering pipeline because apparently I never learn.
&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Download the tool&lt;/a&gt; or read the &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;development blog series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Poly Animated Modern Guns Pack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/low-poly-animated-guns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/low-poly-animated-guns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes developers just need good weapon models without the full template. This pack provides animated,
low-poly guns that work across Unity and Unreal Engine. Each weapon is fully rigged with swappable parts—barrels,
magazines, scopes, and more. The reload animations took longer to perfect than modeling all the weapons combined.
Getting the magazine physics to feel natural while remaining performance-friendly was educational.
Available on &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Unity Asset Store&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Unreal Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Asset Pipeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/automated-asset-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/automated-asset-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing assets across multiple platforms (Unity, Unreal, various marketplaces) was becoming a nightmare.
Every update meant manually exporting for Unity URP, HDRP, Built-in, Unreal Engine versions, packaging for
Gumroad, uploading everywhere, updating docs&amp;hellip; Built a system that handles the entire pipeline with one command.
Sure, it took three weeks to build what would&amp;rsquo;ve taken a few hours to do manually, but now those few hours
happen automatically forever. Read about &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;how the pipeline works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blender Weapon Rigging System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/blender-weapon-rigging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/blender-weapon-rigging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After rigging dozens of weapons manually, I got tired of repeating the same setup process. This Blender add-on
automates weapon rigging, attachment systems, and animation setup. What used to take hours now takes minutes.
The first version tried to automate everything and failed spectacularly on edge cases. The current version handles
the tedious parts while leaving creative control to the artist. Now part of our internal workflow and
&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;available free on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
